javiantonyuste97@gmail.com LinkedIn: Javier Antón Yuste

# JAVIER ANTÓN YUSTE

Telecommunications Engineer from the Polytechnic University of Madrid, currently studying for a Master's Degree in Telecommunications Engineering at the ETSIT-UPM.

I am a person with a very positive character, who always seeks to learn and face new challenges with creativity and proactivity. I have experience in the field of servers/web development and in team management and training in transversal skills.

## **EDUCATION**

2019 - present Master's Degree in Telecommunications Engineering

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

2015 — 2020 Degree in Telecommunications Technologies and

Services Engineering

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

2018 – 2019 Participant of Erasmus+ Program

Warsaw University of Technology

# **SKILLS**

#### **Personal**

Soft Skills Team Management Communication Empathy

#### **Technical**

Servers Web Programming JAVA Python Cloud Computing GNU/Linux

## Languages

Spanish – Native English – B2/C1

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## 2019 Intern at GreenLSI - UPM

I participated as a scholarship holder in an Educational Innovation Project that has been applied to the Degree in Biomedical Engineering, in which I developed a web platform for laboratory gamification, which later became my End of Degree Project.

#### 2020 – present Google Developer Student Club Lead

Developer Student Clubs are university-based community groups for students interested in Google developer technologies. I am leading a DSC composed by 100+ members, being the bridge that connects the available knowledge in the international community with local members.

## 2018 – present Soft Skills Trainer and Facilitator

Trainer and facilitator of sessions with the objective of providing specific training to individuals to help them strengthen their interpersonal skills. To learn how to give these sessions I trained in a course called "Training 4 Trainers", in which more experienced trainers taught me a wide range of topics related to Soft Skills, such as: Emotional Intelligence, Leadership, Team and Project Management, Communication and Presentation Skills, Body Language, etc.

I currently have over 100 hours of experience in both Soft Skills and facilitated sessions.

## 2015 – present Member in EESTEC

EESTEC is an association of students at European level, which promotes cultural exchange among its members and the training of them in professional and personal skills through the organization of events that promote it.

## 2017 — 2018 Local Board at EESTEC LC Madrid - Contact Person

During this year I supervised the projects of the association, formed by more than 50 members, and also acted as a link between the local and international association.

## 2017 - present Coordinator and member at EESTEC International

Coordinator and member of several international teams of EESTEC, whose objective is to develop the association and its members. I had these positions:

- Member of the PR Team, in charge of the external promotion.
- Coordinator of the Angels Team, in charge of supporting the newest committees.
- Member of the OWL Team, in charge of training active members in the international level.

## 2019 — 2020 Fundraising Coordinator in EESTEC LC Madrid

In charge of leading a team of 20 people with the aim of creating professional relationships with companies for collaboration with the association.

## 2019 - 2020 Event organiser

During my time as a member, I have helped organize events every year, having them as the main topic technologies like Artificial Intelligence, Cloud Computing, Cybersecurity, etc.

## 2019 - present Partner in Trainers Forum

Trainers' Forum is an organization that aims to bring together an international community of educators around advanced learning, networking and collaboration opportunities. Here I have been coordinator of Training Alliance Circle, dedicated to networking with other associations, member of the IT team and organizer of several events.

## OTHER INFORMATION OF INTEREST

## 2018 Speaker in AULA 2018 - Do you want to be a Cybersecurity expert?

Presentation made at the AULA 2018 forum, where topics on cybersecurity were explained accompanied by a practical explanation. I went as a volunteer of ETSIT - UPM.

# 2018 & 2020 Teacher at the GNU/Linux Introduction Course

Course given by Eurielec - EESTEC LC Madrid, in which basic concepts about this technology are taught and basic concepts about free software and the community concept are introduced.

## 2005 - 2016 Elementary and Professional Music Education

Specialization in Guitar, by the Professional Conservatory of Music of Segovia.